

George Artikis

Chelmsford, Essex 07464750657 george_artikis@yahoo.com

Solution-driven website developer adept at contributing to highly collaborative work environment, finding solutions and determining customer satisfaction. Proven experience developing consumer-focused websites using HTML, CSS, PHP, JavaScript, SQL and Python. Built products for desktop and mobile app users over 1 year, meeting highest standards for web design, user experience, best practices and speed. Designed and developed web applications across multiple APIs, third-party integrations and databases.

Work Experience

Website Developer

05/2020 to Present

Self Employed

Online

- Optimized company's website and main corporate blog to boost SEO traffic to sites
- Pulled from PHP, SQL, JavaScript and other back-end library knowledge to bolster programming resources.
- Planned website development, converting mockups into usable web presence with HTML, JavaScript, AJAX and JSON coding.
- Coded 5 websites using HTML, CSS, JavaScript, php, SQL and Python.
- Implemented Google-based and other campaigns with slant toward SEO.
- Collected, defined and translated user requirements into project designs and implementation plans.
- Developed landing pages, dashboards and online applications using multiple JavaScript frameworks, and php.
- Designed, developed and implemented software applications for website based on analyzed requirements and understanding of industry technical standards.
- Designed and executed security measures such as firewalls and encryption.
- Collaborated with in-house web designers to create sleek and innovative UI design.
- Maintained strict budgetary and scheduling guidelines to satisfy customers with high-quality, targeted designs.

Retail Sales Assistant

06/2020 to 07/2020

GAME

Chelmsford

Offered each customer top-notch, personal service and polite support to

- boost sales and customer satisfaction.
- Created inviting environment for customers by maintaining store organization and cleanliness.
- Balanced and organized cash register by handling cash, counting change and storing coupons.
- Used consultative sales approach to understand customer needs and recommend relevant offerings.
- Approached each problem with fresh mind and analytical strategies to quickly resolve concerns.
- Answered customer questions regarding merchandise and pricing.
- Aided Greek and Spanish speaking customers, increasing customer loyalty.

Skills

Programming Languages - 5 years

Web development projects - 1 year

Programming - 5 years

Website Development - 1 year

Search Engine Optimisation - 1 year

HTML - 3 years

CSS - 1 year

JavaScript (and frameworks) - 1 year

Php - 1 year

Python - 5 years

SQL - 3 years

Education

Anglo European School

High school or equivalent GSCE's

Essex

09/2014 to 08/2019

Anglo European School

High school or equivalent

International Baccalureate Essex

09/2019 to Present